

TALHA IMRAN

Computer Science Student

PROFILE

20 years young University Student doing Bachelors in Computer Science from BIIT Rawalpindi having a strong grip on Programming Fundamentals and OOP. Also have a 3 months Experience at CSR position. Also have a hands-on Experience with Computer Applications, SQL, java, c++ and have Excellent Communication Skills. Having a Experience of making different projects as listed ahead and attended events and seminars like Flutter Forward Extended, ITCN Asia expo, and ECMAScript Workshop etc.

CONTACT

PHONE:

+92 3405193787

LinkedIn:

/in/talhaimran-pk

EMAIL:

talhaimran207@gmail.com

PROJECTS

RFID based Attendance and Door Locking System
 Used RFID Technology to make a System that prevents
 anyone to pass by a Door without marking attendance.
 As soon as the RFID card is scanned the door opens and
 attendance of the person is sent to a google sheet using
 WIFI.

Rent a Car System

Concepts learnt from Object Oriented Programming and Database Systems were utilized to make a utility software for a Rent a Car Business. Technologies Used were JAVA, SQL and connected them using JDBC.

Grocery Store

Designed a basic grocery store using C++ and Concepts from Programming fundamentals.

EXPERIENCES

X-telecom (Customer Support Representative)

(July-Sep) 2022

Assisted American based customers, addressed inquiries, provided them information about the company's product. Learnt communication, problem-solving, patience and time management.

Teaching Assistant to a Database Professor at University

March'2023-Present

Assisting professor with course materials, grading, student support, lab sessions, classroom management, and collaboration in Workshops.

Vice President Programming Society at University

March'2023-Present

Organized different events, workshops, competitions, and project showcases to promote programming skills and community building.

EDUCATION

Army Public School (2017-19) MATRICULATION (88.18% marks)

F.G Sir Syed College (2019-21) F.Sc Pre-Engineering (63.2% marks)

Barani Institute of Information Technology (Oct'2022-present)

Bachelors of Computer Science (4 years)

CGPA: 4.00 Current Semester: 2nd

Reference: Dr. Munir Ahmed (Deputy Director BIIT) (+92 3005137383)